(513) 290 - 9256 nick@nicholasradford.com San Francisco, CA

What I've worked on

At Euclid Analytics, I've brought my modern javascript experience to an established product and have pushed for our team to use tools and libraries such as ES2015, redux (react) and webpack. The result has been a more modular and extendable code base, which is easier to test.

During my time at WalmartLabs, I spearheaded an initiative to unify CSS styling within Sam's Club called Sherpa. Sherpa was a css library, not dissimilar to Bootstrap, which provided common styles which could be used in responsive designs for Sam's Club.

While at Dell Software, I led a team which built an internal UI toolkit based on jQuery and Backbone, and later transitioned the software into an Angular based directive/service library for building out enterprise applications which adhered to frequently changing requirements from Dell's brand department.

Experience

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, EUCLID ANALYTICS – FEBRUARY 2016 - CURRENT

Helped transition the Insight product to using ES2015 and webpack. Implemented proof-of-concept captive portal UIs for clients. Created a web app to help verify passive data attribution accuracy using express, mysql, and react.

SENIOR MOBILE WEB ENGINEER, WALMART - APRIL 2015 - DECEMBER 2015

Helped transition Sam's Club's desktop website into a new design language, which was a hybrid implementation of JSP and Angular. This work was spread out across a large team, where I was regularly an advocate for good git practices, coding style (and tooling), and tests. Led a css styling initiative to unify css styles across Sam's Club.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT STAFF ENGINEER, DELL – APRIL 2012 - MARCH 2015

Led a team which created and distributed a shared UI Library across teams within Dell. Technologies used include Angular.js, SCSS, CoffeeScript, Grunt/Gulp, Selenium, and Jasmine.

INTERN, QUEST SOFTWARE (DELL) - MAY 2011 - APRIL 2012

Developed plugins for an external facing customer communication forum. Also began work on a jQuery and Backbone based UI toolkit.

Education

Bowling Green State University, Bowling Green Ohio – Bachelors of Science (Incomplete)

Technologies

JAVASCRIPT

ReactJS, Redux, ES2015, ES2016, AngularJS (v1, v2), CoffeeScript, Jasmine, Mocha, Protractor, Node.js, Express, Hapi, Highcharts, D3, Three.js, Babel, webpack, websockets

CSS

CSS Modules, SCSS, LESS, Bootstrap, Foundation, BlessCSS, Responsive Design, Media Queries, CSS Animation

MISC

HTML5, HAML, JADE, GIT, Istanbul, Jenkins, gulp, grunt, npm, bower, agile methodologies, slack/hipchat, GitHub, JIRA, Trello, REST, Ruby on Rails, Python, Flask, MySQL, MongoDB

References

References are available upon request